<file>
<document>
	<title>
    <![CDATA[This Way Up]]>
	</title>
	
	<author>
    <![CDATA[Jon Smith]]>
	</author>
	
	<conference>
    <![CDATA[International Conference on Green Computing]]>
	</conference>

	<abstract>
    <![CDATA[We explore a novel online packet scheduling model related to energy-efficiency in mobile data transport. This model incorporates multiple networks with non-persistent connectivities where we only know which networks are available in the current timestep. When a packet arrives, it specifies a deadline and, for each network, a value it is worth if sent over that network. Our goal is to maximize the total value of packets we send by their deadlines. To encourage energy-efficiency, our model requires that packets have larger values for more energy-efficient networks. We demonstrate low-constant-competitive algorithms for this problem and several restrictions. We also provide lower bounds which closely match our competitive ratios and, under some restrictions, are tight.]]>
	</abstract>

	<url><![CDATA[ local ]]></url>
	<!-- make sure it is local -->
	
	<doi>
    <![CDATA[10.1109/GREENCOMP.2010.5598312]]>
	</doi>
	
	<bibtex>
    <![CDATA[@INPROCEEDINGS{5598312, 
author={A. Coté and A. Meyerson and B. Tagiku}, 
booktitle={International Conference on Green Computing}, 
title={Energy-efficient mobile data transport via online multi-network packet scheduling}, 
year={2010}, 
pages={175-187}, 
keywords={mobile communication;packet radio networks;wireless LAN;energy efficiency;energy efficient mobile data transport;low constant competitive algorithm;multiple network;nonpersistent connectivity;online multinetwork packet scheduling;online packet scheduling model;Chromium;Optimized production technology;energy-efficiency;mobile devices;online algorithms;packet scheduling}, 
doi={10.1109/GREENCOMP.2010.5598312}, 
month={Aug},}]]>
	</bibtex>
</document>

<document>
	<title>
    <![CDATA[Randomized k-server on hierarchical binary trees]]>
	</title>
	
	<author>
    <![CDATA[Aaron Coté; Adam Meyerson; Laura Poplawski]]>
	</author>
	
	<conference>
    <![CDATA[STOC '08]]>
	</conference>

	<abstract>
    <![CDATA[We design a randomized online algorithm for k-server on
binary trees with hierarchical edge lengths, with expected
competitive ratio O(log ∆), where ∆ is the diameter of the
metric. This is one of the first k-server algorithms with
competitive ratio poly-logarithmic in the natural problem
parameters, and represents substantial progress on the randomized
k-server conjecture. Extending the algorithm to
trees of higher degree would give a competitive ratio of
O(log2 ∆ log n) for the k-server problem on general metrics
with n points and diameter ∆.
]]>
	</abstract>

	<url><![CDATA[ local ]]></url>
	<!-- make sure it is local -->
	
	<doi>
    <![CDATA[10.1145/1374376.1374411]]>
	</doi>
	
	<bibtex>
    <![CDATA[@inproceedings{Cote:2008:RKH:1374376.1374411,
 author = {Cot{\'e}, Aaron and Meyerson, Adam and Poplawski, Laura},
 title = {Randomized K-server on Hierarchical Binary Trees},
 booktitle = {Proceedings of the Fortieth Annual ACM Symposium on Theory of Computing},
 series = {STOC '08},
 year = {2008},
 isbn = {978-1-60558-047-0},
 location = {Victoria, British Columbia, Canada},
 pages = {227--234},
 numpages = {8},
 url = {http://doi.acm.org.libproxy2.usc.edu/10.1145/1374376.1374411},
 doi = {10.1145/1374376.1374411},
 acmid = {1374411},
 publisher = {ACM},
 address = {New York, NY, USA},
 keywords = {k-server, online competitive analysis},
} ]]>
	</bibtex>
</document>

<document>
	<title>
    <![CDATA[Teaching oral communication in computer science]]>
	</title>
	
	<author>
    <![CDATA[Vianney Coté]]>
	</author>
	
	<conference>
    <![CDATA[ACM SIGCSE Bulletin]]>
	</conference>

	<abstract>
    <![CDATA[Software analysts currently spend a
large portion of their time communicatin g
with others . Effective communicatio n
skills is of extreme importance if on e
wishes to be an efficient and productive
software analyst . This article describe s
some of the exercises related to ora l
communications that are imposed on ou r
students . Advantages and difficulties ar e
discussed .]]>
	</abstract>

	<url><![CDATA[ local ]]></url>
	<!-- make sure it is local -->
	
	<doi>
    <![CDATA[10.1145/24728.24742]]>
	</doi>
	
	<bibtex>
    <![CDATA[@article{Cote:1987:TOC:24728.24742,
 author = {Cot{\'e}, Vianney},
 title = {Teaching Oral Communication in Computer Science},
 journal = {SIGCSE Bull.},
 issue_date = {June 1987},
 volume = {19},
 number = {2},
 month = jun,
 year = {1987},
 issn = {0097-8418},
 pages = {58--60},
 numpages = {3},
 url = {http://doi.acm.org.libproxy2.usc.edu/10.1145/24728.24742},
 doi = {10.1145/24728.24742},
 acmid = {24742},
 publisher = {ACM},
 address = {New York, NY, USA},}]]>
	</bibtex>
</document>

<document>
	<title>
    <![CDATA[An integrating pedagogical tool based on writing articles]]>
	</title>
	
	<author>
    <![CDATA[Vianney Côté; Guy Custeau]]>
	</author>
	
	<conference>
    <![CDATA[SIGCSE '92]]>
	</conference>

	<abstract>
    <![CDATA[This article describes a teaching method besed on the
writing of review or vulgarization articles by the students in their
fields of study. The best articles are published in a magazine
distributed to data processing managers end practitioners. The
advantages of this method end a list of evaluation criteria are
presented.]]>
	</abstract>

	<url><![CDATA[ local ]]></url>
	<!-- make sure it is local -->
	
	<doi>
    <![CDATA[10.1145/135250.134519]]>
	</doi>
	
	<bibtex>
    <![CDATA[@inproceedings{Cote:1992:IPT:134510.134519,
 author = {C\^{o}t{\'e}, Vianney and Custeau, Guy},
 title = {An Integrating Pedagogical Tool Based on Writing Articles},
 booktitle = {Proceedings of the Twenty-third SIGCSE Technical Symposium on Computer Science Education},
 series = {SIGCSE '92},
 year = {1992},
 isbn = {0-89791-468-6},
 location = {Kansas City, Missouri, USA},
 pages = {38--41},
 numpages = {4},
 url = {http://doi.acm.org.libproxy2.usc.edu/10.1145/134510.134519},
 doi = {10.1145/134510.134519},
 acmid = {134519},
 publisher = {ACM},
 address = {New York, NY, USA},
} ]]>
	</bibtex>
</document>

<document>
	<title>
    <![CDATA[Refining Sowa's conceptual graph theory for text generation]]>
	</title>
	
	<author>
    <![CDATA[Daniel Côté; Bernard Moulin]]>
	</author>
	
	<conference>
    <![CDATA[IEA/AIE '90]]>
	</conference>

	<abstract>
    <![CDATA[In project GENTEXT we aim at developing a system which will be able to
generate texts in the French language, starting from knowledge
structures expressed in the form of extended conceptual graphs. We had
to extend the conceptual graph model mainly because in Sowa’s approach
temporal knowledge is not specified in a uniform way, and, monadic
relations (i.e. PAST, FUTR) are not precise enough for expressing verb
tenses in roman languages such as French, Spanish or Italian.
In our model we use conceptual graphs for describing non-temporal
knowledge structures which are called “states”. Temporal knowledge is
expressed by a temporal label which is related to a state by a “period”
relation (PER).
In order to specify verb tenses we use an approach which was first
proposed by Reichenbach and distinguishes for every statement three
temporal markers : S (time of locutor), E (time at which occurred the
event) and R (time of the temporal reference).
This model is used for specifying conceptual structures from which
sentences are generated in French. ]]>
	</abstract>

	<url><![CDATA[ local ]]></url>
	<!-- make sure it is local -->
	
	<doi>
    <![CDATA[10.1145/98784.98880]]>
	</doi>
	
	<bibtex>
    <![CDATA[@inproceedings{Cote:1990:RSC:98784.98880,
 author = {C\^{o}t{\'e}, Daniel and Moulin, Bernard},
 title = {Refining Sowa's Conceptual Graph Theory for Text Generation},
 booktitle = {Proceedings of the 3rd International Conference on Industrial and Engineering Applications of Artificial Intelligence and Expert Systems - Volume 1},
 series = {IEA/AIE '90},
 year = {1990},
 isbn = {0-89791-372-8},
 location = {Charleston, South Carolina, USA},
 pages = {528--537},
 numpages = {10},
 url = {http://doi.acm.org.libproxy2.usc.edu/10.1145/98784.98880},
 doi = {10.1145/98784.98880},
 acmid = {98880},
 publisher = {ACM},
 address = {New York, NY, USA},
}]]>
	</bibtex>
</document>
</file>




