<document>
	<title>
    <![CDATA[Automated Checking of Web Application Invocations]]>
	</title>

	<author>
    <![CDATA[William G.J. Halfond]]>
	</author>

	<conference>
    <![CDATA[2012 IEEE 23rd International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering]]>
	</conference>

	<abstract>
    <![CDATA[HTTP based invocations allow web application components to communicate among themselves and build dynamic customized web pages. Invocations are widely used by web applications, but are a common source of errors. Existing techniques are only able to verify limited correctness properties of web application invocations and omit key properties, such as an argument's type and value must match its target parameter's domain. This paper presents the first approach for verifying these correctness properties of web application invocations. An empirical evaluation of the technique shows that it is able to identify, with high precision, over 30% more invocation errors than were previously identified and that the approach has a low analysis runtime cost.]]>
	</abstract>

	<url><![CDATA[ local ]]></url>
	<!-- make sure it is local -->

	<doi>
    <![CDATA[10.1109/ISSRE.2012.37]]>
	</doi>

	<bibtex>
    <![CDATA[@INPROCEEDINGS{6405359,
author={W. G. J. Halfond},
booktitle={2012 IEEE 23rd International Symposium on Software Reliability Engineering},
title={Automated Checking of Web Application Invocations},
year={2012},
pages={111-120},
keywords={Internet;program verification;HTTP based invocations;Web application invocations;automated checking;dynamic customized Web pages;Approximation methods;HTML;Java;Runtime;Switches;Syntactics;Target tracking;invocations;program analysis;verification;web applications},
doi={10.1109/ISSRE.2012.37},
ISSN={1071-9458},
month={Nov},}]]>
	</bibtex>
</document>

<document>
	<title>
    <![CDATA[Command-Form Coverage for Testing Database Applications]]>
	</title>

	<author>
    <![CDATA[William G.J. Halfond; Alessandro Orso]]>
	</author>

	<conference>
    <![CDATA[21st IEEE International Conference on Automated Software Engineering ]]>
	</conference>

	<abstract>
    <![CDATA[The testing of database applications poses new challenges for software engineers. In particular, it is difficult to thoroughly test the interactions between an application and its underlying database, which typically occur through dynamically-generated database commands. Because traditional code-based coverage criteria focus only on the application code, they are often inadequate in exercising these commands. To address this problem, we introduce a new test adequacy criterion that is based on coverage of the database commands generated by an application and specifically focuses on the application-database interactions. We describe the criterion, an analysis that computes the corresponding testing requirements, and an efficient technique for measuring coverage of these requirements. We also present a tool that implements our approach and a preliminary study that shows the approach's potential usefulness and feasibility]]>
	</abstract>

	<url><![CDATA[ local ]]></url>
	<!-- make sure it is local -->

	<doi>
    <![CDATA[10.1109/ASE.2006.27]]>
	</doi>

	<bibtex>
    <![CDATA[@INPROCEEDINGS{4019563,
author={W. G. J. Halfond and A. Orso},
booktitle={21st IEEE/ACM International Conference on Automated Software Engineering (ASE'06)},
title={Command-Form Coverage for Testing Database Applications},
year={2006},
pages={69-80},
keywords={database management systems;program diagnostics;program testing;application-database interactions;command-form coverage;database application testing;dynamically-generated database commands;software engineering;test adequacy criterion;Application software;Automata;Data engineering;Database languages;Doped fiber amplifiers;Educational institutions;Feedback;Runtime;Software testing;System testing},
doi={10.1109/ASE.2006.27},
ISSN={1938-4300},
month={Sept},}]]>
	</bibtex>
</document>

<document>
	<title>
    <![CDATA[Energy-directed test suite optimization]]>
	</title>

	<author>
    <![CDATA[William G.J. Halfond; Ding Li; Cagri Sahin; James Clause]]>
	</author>

	<conference>
    <![CDATA[2013 2nd International Workshop on Green and Sustainable Software (GREENS)]]>
	</conference>

	<abstract>
    <![CDATA[Abstract:
Post-deployment in situ testing and validation techniques have become an important means of ensuring the reliability of mobile and embedded systems. However, these techniques do not take into consideration the amount of energy they consume, which is an issue of paramount concern for systems with limited energy budgets. In this paper we propose a new test suite minimization approach that allows developers to generate energy-efficient, minimized test suites. The approach is based on encoding minimization problems as integer linear programming problems. Our empirical evaluation shows that, compared to traditionally generated minimized test suites, the test suites generated by our approach are equally effective in terms of their test coverage, but can realize energy savings of up to 90 %.]]>
	</abstract>

	<url><![CDATA[ local ]]></url>
	<!-- make sure it is local -->

	<doi>
    <![CDATA[10.1109/GREENS.2013.6606423]]>
	</doi>

	<bibtex>
    <![CDATA[@INPROCEEDINGS{6606423,
author={D. Li and C. Sahin and J. Clause and W. G. J. Halfond},
booktitle={2013 2nd International Workshop on Green and Sustainable Software (GREENS)},
title={Energy-directed test suite optimization},
year={2013},
pages={62-69},
keywords={embedded systems;integer programming;linear programming;mobile computing;power aware computing;program testing;embedded systems;encoding minimization problems;energy-directed test suite optimization;energy-efficient minimized test suites;in situ testing;integer linear programming problems;limited energy budgets;mobile systems;test suite minimization approach;validation techniques;Androids;Energy consumption;Energy measurement;Humanoid robots;Instruments;Minimization;Testing;Energy use;Post-deployment validation;Test suite optimization;Testing},
doi={10.1109/GREENS.2013.6606423},
month={May},}]]>
	</bibtex>
</document>

<document>
	<title>
    <![CDATA[OWASP: Protecting Web Applications Using Positive Tainting and Syntax-Aware Evaluation]]>
	</title>

	<author>
    <![CDATA[William G.J. Halfond; Alex Orso; Pete Manolios]]>
	</author>

	<conference>
    <![CDATA[IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering ]]>
	</conference>

	<abstract>
    <![CDATA[Many software systems have evolved to include a Web-based component that makes them available to the public via the Internet and can expose them to a variety of Web-based attacks. One of these attacks is SQL injection, which can give attackers unrestricted access to the databases that underlie Web applications and has become increasingly frequent and serious. This paper presents a new highly automated approach for protecting Web applications against SQL injection that has both conceptual and practical advantages over most existing techniques. From a conceptual standpoint, the approach is based on the novel idea of positive tainting and on the concept of syntax-aware evaluation. From a practical standpoint, our technique is precise and efficient, has minimal deployment requirements, and incurs a negligible performance overhead in most cases. We have implemented our techniques in the Web application SQL-injection preventer (WASP) tool, which we used to perform an empirical evaluation on a wide range of Web applications that we subjected to a large and varied set of attacks and legitimate accesses. WASP was able to stop all of the otherwise successful attacks and did not generate any false positives.]]>
	</abstract>

	<url><![CDATA[ local ]]></url>
	<!-- make sure it is local -->

	<doi>
    <![CDATA[10.1109/TSE.2007.70748]]>
	</doi>

	<bibtex>
    <![CDATA[@ARTICLE{4359474,
author={W. Halfond and A. Orso and P. Manolios},
journal={IEEE Transactions on Software Engineering},
title={WASP: Protecting Web Applications Using Positive Tainting and Syntax-Aware Evaluation},
year={2008},
volume={34},
number={1},
pages={65-81},
keywords={Internet;SQL;security of data;Internet;WASP;Web application SQL-injection preventer;Web-based attacks;positive tainting;software systems;syntax-aware evaluation;Protection mechanisms;Security and Protection},
doi={10.1109/TSE.2007.70748},
ISSN={0098-5589},
month={Jan},}]]>
	</bibtex>
</document>

<document>
	<title>
    <![CDATA[Detection and Localization of HTML Presentation Failures Using Computer Vision-Based Techniques]]>
	</title>

	<author>
    <![CDATA[William G.J. Halfond; Sonal Mahajan]]>
	</author>

	<conference>
    <![CDATA[2015 IEEE 8th International Conference on Software Testing]]>
	</conference>

	<abstract>
    <![CDATA[An attractive and visually appealing appearance is important for the success of a website. Presentation failures in a site's web pages can negatively impact end users' perception of the quality of the site and the services it delivers. Debugging such failures is challenging because testers must visually inspect large web pages and analyze complex interactions among the HTML elements of a page. In this paper we propose a novel automated approach for debugging web page user interfaces. Our approach uses computer vision techniques to detect failures and can then identify HTML elements that are likely to be responsible for the failure. We evaluated our approach on a set of real-world web applications and found that the approach was able to accurately and quickly identify faulty HTML elements.]]>
	</abstract>

	<url><![CDATA[ local ]]></url>
	<!-- make sure it is local -->

	<doi>
    <![CDATA[10.1109/ICST.2015.7102586]]>
	</doi>

	<bibtex>
    <![CDATA[@INPROCEEDINGS{7102586,
author={S. Mahajan and W. G. J. Halfond},
booktitle={2015 IEEE 8th International Conference on Software Testing, Verification and Validation (ICST)},
title={Detection and Localization of HTML Presentation Failures Using Computer Vision-Based Techniques},
year={2015},
pages={1-10},
keywords={Internet;Web sites;computer vision;hypermedia markup languages;program debugging;system recovery;user interfaces;HTML presentation failures;Web page user interface debugging;Web pages;Web site;computer vision;faulty HTML elements;users perception;visually appealing appearance;Browsers;Cascading style sheets;HTML;Layout;Rendering (computer graphics);Visualization;Web pages},
doi={10.1109/ICST.2015.7102586},
ISSN={2159-4848},
month={April},}]]>
	</bibtex>
</document>
